Welcome back to Apush in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, let's go over a few things
right now. The Vietnam War is causing
millions of young men to be drafted. The
Pentagon Papers has exposed the
government lies and caused a mass
distrust. And the Civil Rights Movement
is proving that protesting can work to
change the norm. And so, the result we
see here is the youngsters of society
starting to question authority and
rebel. We already talked about instances
of this like college protests and
marches. But, a very important event I
haven't mentioned is the Kent State
Massacre. Where a large group of
students at Kent State University were
protesting Vietnam. One thing led to
another and four people ended up being
shot and killed by the US National Guard
in the crowd. But, moving on. Now, what
we see is a new variation of left in
society called the Students for a
Democratic Society. Who believed the
government wasn't doing enough socially,
but was too aggressive militarily. This
group criticized things like war,
inequality, and government power. And
the final form of this youth culture is
the formation of a counterculture social
rebellion. This is where you see the
hippies of the '60s rejecting
traditional jobs, gender roles, and
materialism. This will create a more
rebellious informal society. Here is a
good way to remember the hippie
movement. Peace, love, sex, and a whole
lot of grass. Which is slang for lots
and lots and lots of drugs. On the
screen now are AP style questions for
this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.